Amber Chiodini

(402) 516-4822 | amber.park@northwestern.edu | https://github.com/amberchiodini https://www.linkedin.com/in/amber-chiodini-9699b211b/ | Chicago, IL

SUMMARY

Software developer with experience in both frontend and backend technologies. Working towards a Bachelor's in Biological Sciences and a certificate in full stack web development from Northwestern University. Have a strong interest in working in the biotech industry with a passion for building software that contributes to the field of biomedical research and treatment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Northwestern University | Chicago, IL

01/2020 - Present

Coding Bootcamp Student

• Group Project - Eats & Beats

https://github.com/Team-Norm-1/project-1 | https://team-norm-1.github.io/project-1/

- Worked with a team to create an application that brings a unique experience to users by retrieving new music and recipes using APIs.
- Responsible for creating a responsive website using Bulma css.
- Group Project Keep on Giftin'

https://github.com/girl-power-5/ubiquitous-giggle | https://keep-on-giftin.herokuapp.com/

- Worked with a team to create a full-stack application that reminds the user of certain dates to send friends and family gifts or cards.
- Responsible for building out the database using MySQL for back and frontend communication.

Northwestern University | Chicago, IL

01/2020 - Present

Research Technologist 1

- Follows predefined protocols, procedures, regulations, Good Clinical and Good Laboratory Practices, and conducts standard and repetitive experiments and completes basic troubleshooting techniques.
- Sets-up, operates, and maintains standard lab equipment.
- Records observations and measurements and collects and compiles data in a research lab.
- Communicates with the lab manager about inventory or mechanical discrepancies within the lab.

Northwestern University | Chicago, IL

05/2019 - 01/2020

Animal Care Technician 2

- Conducts daily health checks and feedings for zebrafish (*Danio rerio*).
- Maintains effectiveness and cleanliness of the aquatic housing systems by replacing filters and performing water quality tests.
- Communicates with researchers and supervisors via email or phone for animal health updates or mechanical discrepancies within the facility.
- Conducts a weekly census count for the Procurement, Receiving, and Census staff (PRC).
- Reviews and complies with all standard operating procedures and Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee guidelines pertaining to the fish facility.

University of Chicago | Chicago, IL

08/2019 - 08/2020

Animal Care Technician 1

- Conducted daily animal health checks and feedings for mice (*Mus musculus*).
- Maintained effectiveness and cleanliness of the rodent housing system by replacing cages and other equipment on a bi-weekly basis.

- Followed principal investigator's instructions per special diets or care for the mice.
- Conducted a weekly census count for the Procurement, Receiving, and Census staff (PRC).
- Reviewed and complied with all standard operating procedures and Institutional Animal Care and Use

EDUCATION

BS Northwestern University | Chicago, IL | Weinberg College Studying biological sciences.

08/2019 - Present

CERT Northwestern University | Chicago, IL | School of Professional Studies Learning full-stack web development.

09/2020 - Present

SKILLS

• HTML/CSS

• Bootstrap

• React.js

JavaScript

MySQL

MongoDB

• Node.js

GitHub

• Agile Methodology

Microsoft Office

Responsive Design

Collaboration